John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Corporate Structure, RG 1 FA1793
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Board of Trustees, 1950-2019; 1; 33.99 Cubic Feet 87 letter document boxes and 5 half-letter boxes
  - Meetings, 1950-2019; 6; 11.01 Cubic Feet 28 letter document boxes, 2 half-letter box
    - Board Books, 1986-2009; 2
      - Board Book, 1993 September 21 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
        Writeups of approved grants for: Chrysalis House, Akron Blind Center and Workshop, Baldwin County Council on Substance Abuse, Saint Paul Chamber of Commerce Foundation, Mentors Project of Bibb County, Summit County Adult Literacy Council, Fund for Philadelphia, Metropolitan Career Center, Advocates for Children in Court, North Carolina Center for Nonprofit Organizations, Parents Helping Parents, Emergency Housing Consortium of Santa Clara County, Goodwill Industries-Manasota, Timpany Center, Bill Wilson Marriage and Family Counseling Center, St. Paul Chamber Orchestra Society, National Museum of American Jewish History, Taller Puertorriqueno, San Jose Stage Company, Community Housing Services, Drueding Center, Police Athletic League of Philadelphia, Holy Redeemer and Nazareth Home Health Services, Arkansas River Foundation, Friends of WLRN, Opera Company of Philadelphia, Act 2, Public Broadcasting of Northeast Indiana, Lutheran Social Services of South Dakota, Centre County United Way, The United Health Foundation, Boys and Girls Club of South Central Kansas, The Salvation Army Tallahassee, Headwaters Park Commission, Friends of the Parks in Fayette County, Philadelphia College of Pharmacy and Science, Cuban American National Council, Detroit Cities in Schools, Charlotte Trolley, Michigan Opera Theatre, Children's Concert Society of Akron, Operation Get Down, Haven Center, Big Brothers-Big Sisters of Greater Tallahassee, Community Partnership for the Homeless, Florida Dance Association, Miami Light Project, Association of Youth Museums, Paul Taylor Dance Foundation, Southern Arts Federation, Group I Acting Company, Milkweed Editions, American Association for Higher Education, Florida Audubon Society, Accountants for the Public Interest, Mount Union College, Bibb County Public Schools, Akron-Summit County Public Library, Stanford University Department of Communication, National Conference of Editorial Writers Foundation, University of Georgia Foundation, University of Missouri School of Journalism, University of Florida Foundation, International Museum of Cartoon Art, Helping Miami Rebuild, Shake-a-Leg, United Way of Dade County, Interfaith Coalition for the Andrew Recovery Effort. Writeups of negative responses to proposals are also included.
      - Board Book, 1993 December 14 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
        Writeups of approved grants for: Young Horizons, St. Peter Claver School, Johnson Technical Institute, Christmas in April USA, St. Paul Chamber Orchestra Society, Peabody Historical Society, Discovery Center of Duluth, Fort Wayne Philharmonic Orchestra, Embassy Theatre Foundation, Caldwell Theatre Company, Pennsylvania Ballet Association, Opera Guild of Greater Miami, Florida Department of Natural Resources, Goodwill Industries of Santa Clara, Cities in Schools of Long Beach, Morehead State University, Health Help, Monerey Bay Aquarium Foundation, Theatreworks, San Jose Taiko Group, Akron Zoological Park, Florida Philharmonic Orchestra, Opportunities Industrialization Center West, South Carolina Arts Foundation 1989, Northwest Indiana Symphony Society, Akron Art Museum, East Kentucky Economic Development and Jobs Creation Corporation, Lexington Habitat for Humanity, Kevin Coleman Foundation, Goodwill Industries of Akron, Akron-Canton Regional Foodbank, YMCA of Akron, Central Summit County Choral Society, Cass Community United Methodist Church and Center, Reach, Habitat for Humanity Metro Detroit, Oakland Family Services, Operation Able of Michigan, Daily Bread Food Bank, The Maude Carpenter Children's Home, Westville Historic Handicrafts, Long Beach Youth Centers, YMCA of Long Beach, Milledgeville-Baldwin County Rape Crisis Center, The Family Shelter, Emergency Family Assistance Association, Clinica Campesina Family Health Services, Delray Beach Center for Technology Enterprise and Development, Methodist Home of the South Georgia Conference, Medcen Foundation, Endowment Fund of Lake County, Palmetto Conservation Foundation, Community Harvest Food Bank of Northeast Indiana, Greater Akron Musical Association, Kids Voting, Haitian Refugee Center, Washington Project for the Arts, Dade Women's Welfare Coalition, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, United States Peace Corps, United Negro College Fund, Impact II-The Teachers Network, College of St. Scholastica, Cumberland College, Florida International University Foundation, Heritage College, University of Akron Foundation, University of Colorado at Boulder, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, University of Southern Mississippi, University of St. Thomas, Columbus College, Commonwealth Partnership, Southern Newspaper Publishers Association Foundation, Asian American Journalists Association, The Institute for Journalism Education, Committee for the Study of the American Electorate, American Society of Newspaper Editors Foundation, World Press Freedom Committee, World Press Institute, University of Maryland Foundation, Northwestern University, Education Writers Association, University of Michigan Department of Communication, The University of Texas at Austin, United Way of America, Local Initiatives Support Corporation, The Foundation Center National Office, NAACP Special Contribution Fund, National Center for Family Literacy, Collins Center for Public Policy, National Urban League, John Carroll University, National Community Development Initiative, Dade Community Foundation, St. Paul Foundation, Fort Wayne Community Foundation, Central Carolina Community Foundation, Philadelphia Foundation, Community Foundation of Santa Clara County, Duluth-Superior Area Foundation, Community Foundation of Southeastern Michigan, Foundation for the Carolinas, Akron Community Foundation, Greater Wichita Community Foundation, California Community Foundation, Boy Scouts of America South Florida Council, Children's Home Society of Florida Southeastern Division, Habitat for Humanity of Greater Miami. Writeups for negative responses to proposals are also included.
      - Board Book, 1994 March 23 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
      - Board Book, 1994 June 21 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
        Writeups of approved grants for: Thomas Eakins House Cultural Center and Museum, Musical Arts Association-The Cleveland Orchestra, Replication and Program Services, Interval Brotherhood Homes Corp, Manatee Opportunity Council, Turnstone Center for Disabled Children and Adults, Philabundance, Leon County School District Foundation, Fort Lauderdale Lighthouse for the Blind, Children's Health Council of the Mid-Peninsula, International Book Project, Manatee County Nursery School, Minnesota Indian Primary Residential Treatment Center, Western Reserve Historical Society, Renaissance Home Health Care, Charlotte-Mecklenburg Historic Preservation Fund, Tierra y Esperanza Para la Comunidad Humana Organization, Networkarts Philadelphia, Penumbra Theatre, The School District of Philadelphia, Eastfield Ming Quong Foundation, Mosaic, The Theatre of the Republic, George E. Ohr Arts and Cultural Center, Brandywine Graphic Workshop, KTEH TV Foundation, Mexican Heritage Corporation, Jewish Community Center of the Greater Saint Paul Area, Human Services Division/Pierre Toussaint Haitian Catholic Center, Impact Seminars for Youth, Detroit Neighborhood Housing Services, Harvest Hope Food Bank, P.A.C.E. Center for Girls, Habitat for Humanity of Boulder Valley, Goodwill Industries of Greater Wichita, Boys and Girls Clubs of Central Georgia, Hands on Miami, San Jose Urban Ministry, Mobile Meals Foundation, The Grand Forks Foundation for Education, Youth Living Centers, Akron Rotary Camp for Crippled Children, Metrolina Food Bank, University of Michigan Ann Arbor, Baldwin County School District, City Center Ballet of San Jose, Dave and Mary Alper Jewish Community Center, The Children's Place and Connor's Nursery, Corporation for Educational Radio and Television, Gallaudet University, Lyric Opera of Chicago, Non-Traditional Casting Project, School of American Ballet, WGBH Educational Foundation, D.C. Wheel Productions, Baskervill Ministries, American Association for Higher Education, Imapct II, Southern Scholarship Foundation, American Press Institute, Pennsylvania State University School of Communications, Committee to Protect Journalists, Ohio State University, The Ohio University Foundation, West Virginia Graduate College Foundation, John Carroll University Council for Aid to Education. Writeups of negative responses to proposals are also included.
      - Board Book, 1994 September 20 (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
        Writeups of approved grants for: Margaret E. Wilson Foundation (Goodwood Plantation), Services for Developmentally Disabled of Long Beach, Homeless Care Force Incorporated, Long Beach Civic Light Opera Association, North Star Educational Initiative, Chopin Foundation of the United States, The Friends of McConnell Springs, Goodwill Industries of Long Beach and South Bay, Centre Hall Area Branch Library Association, Settlement Music School of Philadelphia, Lake County Child Abuse Prevention Council, Villanova University, Ivy Tech Foundation, Richardville, YMCA of Charlotte and Mecklenburg, Cooperative Ministry, Adult Abuse Community Services, Habilitation Center for the Handicapped, Shakespeare San Francisco, Advent Group Ministries, Historic Rosedale Foundation, Cityteam Ministries, Community Foundation Macon, The Peopling of Philadelphia Collaborative, Children's Television Workshop, Big Brothers/Big Sisters of America, United Way of the Bluegrass, Center for Urban Resources, Michigan Dyslexia Institute, Philadelphia Drama Guild, Greater Akron Musical Association, Pennsylvania Young Playwrights Program, Women in Distress of Broward County, Michigan Opera Theatre, Friends of WLRN, Friends of the Park, Gulf Coast Opera Theatre, South Carolina State Museum Foundation, Minnesota Program Development, Public Library of Charlotte and Mecklenburg County, North Carolina Performing Arts Center at Charlotte Foundation, Children's Concert Society of Akron, People's Light and Theatre Company, The Nelson-Atkins Museum of Art, Wolf Trap Foundation for the Performing Arts, Cal Performances (University of California Berkeley), Buffalo Bill Memorial Association, Association of American Colleges, Ohio Dominican College, The University of Alabama, The Independent Journalism Foundation, The University of Maryland Foundation, Marine Biological Laboratory, Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theatre Center, American Society of Newspaper Editors Foundation, Duke University, Metropolitan Atlanta Community Foundation, The Asheville School, University of Georgia Foundation, Mount Union College, The Collins Center for Public Policy, Junior League of Akron Ohio, YWCA of Brunswick Georgia, Paducah Junior College, Knight Commission for Intercollegiate Athletics, Wolfsonian Foundation, Junior League of Miami. Writeups for Immunization Initiative grants to: Visiting Nurse Association of Northwest Indiana, S.O.S. Health Care, St. Luke's Midland Regional Medical Center, United Way of Central Carolinas, TMH Regional Medical Center, Junior League of Akron, Bibb County Department of Family and Children's Services, Down-town Wichita Kiwanis Foundation, Boulder County Health Department, Fort Wayne Community Schools-Community Programs Division, Kids in Common, Saint Louis County Health Department, The Children's Hospital, United Way of Dade County, Alliance for South Carolina's Children, HRS/Palm Beach County Public Health Unit, Georgia College Foundation, Grand Forks Public Health Department, Family Health Services, MHG Development Foundation, Columbus Department of Public Health, HRS/Manatee County Public Health Unit, March of Dimes Birth Defects Foundation (Southeast Michigan), The Children's Clinic, Children's Hospital Foundation, St. Christopher's Hospital for Children. Writeups of negative responses to proposals are also included.
      - Board Book, 1994 December 14 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
        Writeups of approved grants for: California State University, Arts and Science Council Charlotte Mecklenburg, St. Patrick Senior Center, Gernation of Promise Program, Manatee County Rural Health Services, National Urban League, Barry University, St. Catharine College, International Institute of Akron, NAACP Special Contribution Fund, Northwest Interfaith Movement, Association for Urban Training Opportunities, Giarretto Institute, Public Allies: The National Center for Careers in Public Life, Akron Art Museum, Haven of Rest Ministries, The Mid-Peninsula YWCA, A Child's Place of Charlotte, Pennsylvania Ballet Association, The Mississippi 2020 Network, Troy State University Foundation, United Arts Services, Greater Miami Opera, Mountain Maternal Health League Planned Parenthood, Theatre Macon, Boulder Bach Festival, Florida History Associates, Museum of Science, Forgotten Harvest, The Columbus Museum, Community Care Services, Richland Memorial Hospital Foundation, Open Door Community House, Jewish Family Service of Greater Miami, Macon Area Habitat for Humanity, United Way of Manatee County, South Dade Immigration Association, Boys and Girls Clubs of the Big Bend, Boys and Girls Club of Baldwin County, Mid-America All-Indian Center, Greater Lakewood Community Hospice, Center for Community Self-Help, Detroit Rescue Mission Ministries, The Salvation Army Wichita, Act II Productions, Community Foundation for Southeastern Michigan, Each One-Reach One, Long Beach Bar Foundation, The Cerebral Palsy Research Foundation, Florida Philharmonic Orchestra, Community Foundation of Santa Clara County, The Philadelphia Foundation, The Community Foundation of Sarasota County, Community Foundation for Palm Beach and Martin Counties, The Washington Drama Society (Arena Stage), Opera America, Old Salem, The Library of Congress, Minnesota Composers Forum, Public Radio International, The Night Kitchen, The Art Institute of Chicago, The Studio Museum in Harlem, Houston Grand Opera Association, The National Faculty and the Phi Beta Kappa Society, United Negro College Fund, The Galef Institute, Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University, Gallaudet University, Haverford College, Indiana University Northwest, Johns Hopkins University, Mercer University, Northern State University, Stetson University, Robert C. Maynard Institute for Journalism Education, World Press Institute, International Press Institute, Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York, The University of Maryland Foundation, The Foundation Center National Office, United Way of Central Georgia, East Palo Alto Teen Home, Lexington Rotary Club Endowment. Writeups of negative responses to proposals are also included.
      - Board Book, 1995 April 18 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
        Writeups of approved grants for: Young Women's Christian Association of Gary, Delaware Valley Community Reinvestment Fund, Ohio Chamber Ballet, Cities in Schools of Long Beach, Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Accountants for the Public Interest, Saint Joseph's Carpenter Society, Cities in Schools of Charlotte Mecklenburg, Abstinence the Better Choice, Summit House, Cuyahoga Valley Preservation and Scenic Railway Association, Dade Women's Welfare Coalition, Aberdeen Area Literary Council, The Los Angeles Educational Partnership, Bushfire Theatre of Performing Arts, Philadelphia Theatre Company, Arts Council of Santa Clara County, Park Square Theatre, Summit County Historical Society, Opera San Jose, Philadelphia Maritime Museum, Please Touch Museum, The Devereaux Foundation, Commonbond Communities, Boys and Girls Club of St. Paul, Boys and Girls Club of Miami, Appalshop, Eton Academy, The Columbia Art Association, Angela Hospice Home Care, Hope Center, Valley Forge Specialized Educational Services Corp., Executive Service Corps of the Delaware Valley, Starr Commonwealth, Columbus Alliance for Battered Women, Boys Club of Columbus and Phenix City, Boys and Girls Club of Fort Wayne, Presbyterian Child Welfare Agency, San Jose Day Nursery, Associated Services for the Blind, Pine to Prairie Girl Scout Council, Fourth Planning and Development District Commission, SPURS Therapeutic Riding Center, Family Counseling Center of Central Georgia, Leadership Long Beach, People's Clinic, Friends of South Manatee Library, Wichita-Sedgwick County Cities in Schools, Manatee County Volunteer Services, Northwest Wisconsin Community Services Agency, Florida Studio Theatre, Northern Waters Library Service, Trustus, Embassy Theatre Foundation, Girl Scout Council of Tropical Florida, Greater Miami Service Corps, Harriet Tubman Historical and Cultural Museum, Boy Scouts of America Indian Waters Council, Up with Down Syndrome Foundation, United Way of Palm Beach County, Wayne State University, Cuban American National Council, Boys and Girls Clubs of Broward County, Duluth Economic Development Authority, Hillsdale College, St. Paul's Episcopal Church, Huron Valley Boys and Girls Club, Tri-County Habitat for Humanity of Central Pennsylvania, Philadelphia Museum of Art, Miami Light Project, Arc Duluth, Fayette County Board of Education, Wichita Public Schools, South Florida Jail Ministries, Kids Voting USA, Midsummer Macon and Macon Neighborhood Arts, Riverfront Redevelopment Corporation. Writeups of negative responses to proposals are also included.
      - Board Book, 1995 June 20 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
        Writeups of approved grants for: The Wolfsonian Foundation, YMCA of Philadelphia and vicinity, Ransom Everglades School, Moshannon Valley YMCA, Children's Dental Foundation, Deaf Service Center of Manatee Sarasota Counties, Habitat for Humanity of Greater Akron, Boy Scouts of America Great Trail Council, COMPAS, St. John Hospital and Medical Center, Evergreen Children's Services, Prairie Harvest Human Services Foundation, Renaissance Home Health Care, The Free Library of Philadelphia, Cities in Schools Philadelphia, Arts United of Greater Fort Wayne, Operation Able of Michigan, Fort Wayne Educational Foundation, Palm Beach County Schools, Manatee County Nursery School, East Side Neighborhood Development Company, Wildacres Retreat, Germantown Historical Society, The Village of Arts and Humanities, Center for Training and Careers, Goodwill Industries of Kentucky, American Music Theater Festival, First Unitarian Church of San Jose, People Acting in Community Together, Akron Summit Community Action Agency, Ogontz Avenue Revitalization Corporation, Twin Cities Public Television, Uptown Columbus, Consortium for Affordable Home Financing, Daily Bread Food Bank, Emergency Housing Consortium of Santa Clara County, Cleveland Institute of Music, Georgetown College, Educational Referral Center, North Carolina Performing Arts Center at Charlotte Foundation, Dade Public Education Fund, Center for the Fine Arts Association, Boy Scouts of America Calumet Council, San Jose Civic Light Opera, Friends of the Cerritos Center for the Performing Arts, The Bakehouse Art Complex, Mennonite Housing Rehabilitation Services, Detroit Renaissance Foundation, Community Anti-Drug Coalitions of America, Kansas Newman College, Manatee Opportunity Council, South Florida Super Bowl Host Committee Foundation. Writeups for negative responses to proposals are also included.
      - Board Book, 1995 September (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
        Writeups of approved grants for: San Jose Historical Museum Association, National Constitution Center, Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC), Detroit Historical Society, Arden Theatre Company, Timpany Center, Boys and Girls Clubs of Long Beach, Westside Neighborhood Development Corporation, The Prichard Committee for Academic Excellence, Lighthouse of Oakland County, Deaf Services Bureau, Zion Lutheran Urban Academy, Stuart Robinson School Alumni Association, Columbus '96 Support Committee, Palm Beach County Association for Retarded Citizens, Mercy Hospice of Horry County, Fayette County Local Development Corporation, Early Childhood Association of Florida, Little Haiti Housing Association, San Juan Bautista Child Development Center, Community Stabilization Project, Miami Rescue Mission, American Red Cross (Greater Miami Chapter), Citizens and Business Against Crime, High Scope Educational Research Foundation, Long Beach Symphony Association, City Year, Hope Haven, Detroit Zoological Society, Congreso De Latinos Unidos, Life Directions, Tallahassee Urban League, Michigan Opera Theatre, Coconut Grove Playhouse State Theatre of Florida Corporation, Gulf Coast Women's Center, The Saint Paul Foundation, Children's Theatre of Charlotte, Young Actors Theatre of Tallahassee, Long Beach Regional Arts Foundation, Teatro Nuevo New Theatre, Kentucky Folk Art Center, American Youth Work Center, Greater Atlanta Chamber Foundation, Children's Science Explorium, Kids Voting USA, United Way of Horry County, Children's Concert Society of Akron, Greater Akron Musical Association, Northwest Indiana Forum Foundation, Florida Philharmonic Orchestra. Negative responses to: Norton Gallery and School of Art, Nationalities Service Center of Philadelphia, Southeastern Guide Dogs, Melpomene Institute for Women's Health Research, Commonplace, Goodwill Industries of Santa Clara, Haven Center, Minnesota Teen Challenge, Human Services Division/Pierre Toussaint Haitian Catholic Center, Perspectives, Courage Center, Educating Children for Parenting, Kenny Michigan Rehabilitation Foundation, Foundation for the Multihandicapped Blind and Deaf of South Carolina, Spring Garden School, Thomas D. Clark Foundation, Shelter for the Homeless, Detroit Institute for Children, Reading and Language Arts Institute, Impact Seminars for Youth, Institute for Education and Advocacy, Eastern Michigan University, San Jose State University Foundation, Florida State University, Apalachicola Maritime Institute, Berea Child Care Association, Domestic Violence Emergency Services of Gateway, Women's Association for Women's Alternatives, The Fabric Workshop, The Franklin Institute, Children's Hospital at Stanford Family Center, Volunteers of America Delaware Valley, Catholic Charities of San Jose, Habitat for Humanity--North Central Philadelphia, The Carlisle Project, Delaware Valley Association for the Education of Young Children, Community Concert Association, The Florida Museum of Hispanic and Latin American Art, YWCA of Lexington, Manatee Religious Services, Youth Development Services, Camp Fire Boys and Girls Minnesota Council, Youth News Service of Los Angeles Bureau, Florida Prevention Association, West Perrine Community Development Corporation, Huntington-Whitley County Group Home, He Cares Ministries, One Church-One Offender, St. Thomas University, United Way of Dade County, Light Factory, University Musical Society, Walker Art Center, Miami Symphony Orchestra, Coral Gables International Festival of Craft Arts, Miami Book Fair International, Kentucky Center for the Arts, Okaloosa-Walton Community College, Project Light of Manatee, Henry Clay Memorial Foundation, Unity on the Bay, Boy Scouts of America (Indianhead Council), Georgia Childrens Home, Interfaith Center for Racial Justice, Le Jardin Community Center, Charlotte-Mecklenburg Education Foundation, and the Center for Family and Child Enrichment. Also included are two memos prepared by Raybin Associates re: issues of importance when interviewing for Foundation members. Three folders.
      - Board Book, 1995 December 12 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)